Benjamin Stratton

Web Developer

Benstratton100@gmail.com | +1(808)646-1106 | www.linkedin.com/in/benjaminbstratton | Portfolio: www.benjamin-stratton.com

Summary

A data-driven Software Engineer combining boot camp experience and a sales/marketing background to develop high-performing, top-quality full-stack applications.

Technical Skills

Javascript, Python, HTML/CSS, NoSQL, SQL, React, Node.js, Django, Bootstrap, Material UI, Tailwind, JSON, MongoDB, Postgresql, Agile Methodologies, Unit Testing, Github, VScode.

Education

General Assembly | Software Engineering Immersive

Graduated 2023

Successfully completed an intensive 500+ hour Software Engineering Immersive course at the top of my class, acquiring expertise in JavaScript, Python, and relational and non-relational databases (SQL/NoSQL).

Western Carolina University | Integrated Health Sciences

Attended 2018 - 2021

Completed over 90 credit hours toward a BA in Integrated Health Sciences.

Work Experience

Build Your Practice | Business Consultant

April 2022 - December 2022

Build Your Practice is a consulting firm that offers assistance to mental health clinicians seeking to establish and sustain successful private practices.

- Assumed the responsibility of devising and directing lead generation strategies, as well as providing expert guidance throughout the entire sales cycle.
- Revamped the sales cycle and executed novel systems resulting in a 500% surge in sales.

Freelance | High Ticket Sales Closer

August 2021 - April 2022

- Assumed the onus of proactively identifying and nurturing qualified leads through the intricacies of the sales funnel, with the overarching goal of meeting and exceeding weekly and monthly key performance indicators (KPIs).
- Demonstrated an exceptional aptitude for high-value sales by surpassing the milestone of \$500k in cash collected within the initial eight months of my tenure.

Projects

Promptopia - Social Media App | https://github.com/benjaminstratton/ai prompt sharing

- Promptopia is an app where you can share creative and innovative AI prompts.
- Created completely with Next.js and MongoDB, including Google authentication, performance rendering for SEO optimization, a search field, full CRUD, and more!

Push-It - Workout App | https://github.com/benjaminstratton/pushIt workoutApp

- Push-it was born to do two fundamental things: provide sample workout routines and a space to track workouts.
- Created with Postgres, Node.js, Express.js, React, Material UI, JWT, and bcrypt.
- Includes user authentication, email and password verification, private routes, a user quiz that generates custom feedback, and full CRUD for storing information.